Inventory of the Paul B. Henze papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Horn of Africa File, 1959-2009 (Box 59-143)
  - Printed matter, 1960-2007
    - By issuing organization, 1963-2008
      - Tigray Development Association, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 136: 6)
      - Tigray People's Liberation Front (TPLF), 1981-1989 (Box-folder 136: 7-12)
      - Union of Ethiopian Democrats in Ohio, 1991 (Box-folder 136: 13)
      - United Nations Development Program, 1988 (Box-folder 136: 14)
      - United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, 1998 (Box-folder 136: 15)
      - United States Agency for International Development (USAID), 1968-1992 (Box-folder 137: 1)
      - United States Department of Commerce, 1963, 1983 (Box-folder 137: 2)
      - United States Department of State, 1965 (Box-folder 137: 3-4)
      - United States Embassy (Ethiopia), 1968-1992 (Box-folder 137: 5-6)
      - United States Institute of Peace, 1999 (Box-folder 137: 7)
      - Universität Wien, 2006 (Box-folder 137: 8)
      - Worker's Party of Ethiopia, 1986 (Box-folder 137: 9)
      - World Bank, 1984 (Box-folder 137: 10)
      - World Bank, 1985-2004 (Box-folder 138: 1-12)
      - World Employment Programme, 1979 (Box-folder 139: 1)
      - World Food Programme, 1989 (Box-folder 139: 2)
      - Yenesanet Medrek, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 139: 3)
    - By periodical title, 1960-2007
      - Addis Negari Gazeta, 1994 November (Box-folder 139: 4)
      - Addis Tribune, 1995 (Box-folder 139: 5)
      - Adulis, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 139: 6)
      - Africa Report, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 139: 7)
      - Africa Watch, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 139: 8)
      - The African Communist, 1978 (Box-folder 139: 9)
      - African Studies in Frankfurt, 1990 (Box-folder 139: 10)
      - Birritu, 1988 (Box-folder 139: 11)
      - Capital, 2005 (Box-folder 139: 12)
      - CRS Report for Congress, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 139: 13)
      - Current Digest of the Soviet Press, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 139: 14)
      - Eritrea in Struggle: Newsletter of Association of Eritrean Students in North America, 1978 (Box-folder 140: 1)
      - Ethiopia Profile, 1982 (Box-folder 140: 2)
      - The Ethiopian, 1992 (Box-folder 140: 3)
      - The Ethiopian Examiner, 1993 (Box-folder 140: 4-5)
      - The Ethiopian Herald, 1972-1973, 1987, 1997 (Box-folder 140: 6-8)
      - Ethiopian Perspective, 1985 (Box-folder 140: 9)
      - Ethiopian Reporter, 2005 May (Box-folder 140: 10)
      - Ethiopian Review, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 140: 11)
      - Ethioscope, 1996 (Box-folder 140: 12)
      - Faces, 1995 (Box-folder 140: 13)
      - Fortune, 2005 (Box-folder 140: 14)
      - Horizon, 1983 (Box-folder 140: 15)
      - Horn of Africa Bulletin, 1992 (Box-folder 140: 16)
      - Horn of Africa Report, 1990 (Box-folder 140: 17)
      - Imbylta, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 140: 18-19)
      - Iwnet, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 141: 1)
      - The Kindling Point, circa 1985 (Box-folder 141: 2)
      - Kirs, 1994 (Box-folder 141: 3)
      - Medrek, 1990 (Box-folder 141: 4)
      - The Monitor (Addis Ababa), 1995, 2000 (Box-folder 141: 5)
      - Negarit Gazeta, 1983-1991 (Box-folder 141: 6-9)
      - New Ethiopia, 1991 (Box-folder 141: 10)
      - Nubica, 1990 (Box-folder 141: 11)
      - Quarterly Yekatit, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 141: 12)
      - The Reporter, 2005 (Box-folder 141: 13)
      - Sinet Newsletter, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 141: 14)
      - Sub-Saharan Africa Reports, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 141: 15)
      - The Sub-Saharan Informer, 2007 (Box-folder 141: 16)
      - Sudan Democratic Gazette, 1998 (Box-folder 141: 17)
      - The Sun, 2000 (Box-folder 141: 18)
      - Tatek Review: Journal of the Revolutionary Army of Socialist Ethiopia, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 141: 19)
      - Tesfa, 1985 (Box-folder 141: 20)
      - Third World Reports, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 141: 21)
      - Traditio: Studies in Ancient and Medieval History, Thought and Religion, 1960 (Box-folder 141: 22)
      - Washington Review of Strategic and International Studies, 1978 (Box-folder 141: 23)
      - Whydah Newsletter, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 141: 24)
    - By form, 1960s-1990s
      - Calendar of Ethiopian art, 1969 (Box-folder 142: 5)
      - Commemorative postage stamps from Ethiopia, 1996 (Box-folder 142: 6)
      - Tourism brochures and pamphlets from Ethiopia, 1960s-1990s (Box-folder 142: 7-10)
    - In Amharic, 1980s (Box-folder 142: 11-12)
  - Friends of Ethiopia file, 1985-1997
    - Correspondence, 1985-1997 (Box-folder 143: 1-2)
    - Bylaws, memoranda, and reports, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 143: 3-4)
    - Newsletters, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 143: 5-15)
- Caucasus File, 1859-2009 (Box 144-162)
  Contains correspondence, speeches and writings, conference files, notes, reports, programs, travel files, photographs, and printed matter.
  - Correspondence, 1981-2008
    - South Ossetia war correspondence, 2008 August 6-30 (Box-folder 144: 1)
      Correspondence between Henze, Thomas Goltz, Paul Goble, Tedo Japaridze, and S. Enders Wimbush regarding the conflict between Russia and Georgia.
    - Routine, 1983-1998
      - A-H (Box-folder 144: 2)
      - I-Y (Box-folder 144: 3)
    - Akaev, Vakhit, 1993 (Box-folder 144: 4)
    - Armenian National Committee (Raffi Hamparian), 1993 (Box-folder 144: 5)
    - Baker, James Addison, 1991 (Box-folder 144: 6)
    - Colarusso, John, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 144: 7)
    - Dragadze, Tamara, 1994 (Box-folder 144: 8)
    - Dudaev, Dzhokhar, circa 1992 (Box-folder 144: 9)
      Photocopies of two letters to Boris Yeltsin.
    - Gammer, Moshe, 1981, 1994 (Box-folder 144: 10)
    - Goltz, Thomas, 1995 (Box-folder 144: 11)
    - Japaridze, Tedo, 1992-2008 (Box-folder 144: 12)
    - Kazan, Yanal, 1993 (Box-folder 144: 13)
    - Kupelian, Louise, 1990 (Box-folder 144: 14)
    - Oberg, Jan, 1992 (Box-folder 144: 15)
    - Reddaway, Peter, 1988, 1993 (Box-folder 144: 16)
    - Reddaway, Peter, 1988, 1993 (Box-folder 144: 17)
    - Rutland, Peter, 2003 (Box-folder 145: 1)
    - Shevardnadze, Eduard, 1992 (Box-folder 145: 2)
    - Starr, S. Frederick, 2008 (Box-folder 145: 3)
    - Tsereteli, Mamuka, 1990s (Box-folder 145: 4)
    - Wimbush, S. Enders, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 145: 5)
      Relates to Georgia. See also: Box 6.
  - Speeches and writings, 1958-2008
    In chronological order and thereunder alphabetically.
    - "The Shamil Problem,", 1958 (Box-folder 145: 6)
    - "Fire and Sword in the Caucasus: The 19th Century Resistance of the North Caucasian Mountaineers,", 1983 July (Box-folder 145: 7)
    - "Marx'in Rus ve Müslümanlar'a Dair Yazılarından Seçmeler,", 1984 September 15 (Box-folder 145: 8)
    - "Medieval Georgia," Smithsonian lecture, 1984 November 6 (Box-folder 145: 9)
    - "The Spectre and Implications of Internal Nationalist Dissent: Historical and Functional Comparisons,", 1985 (Box-folder 145: 10)
    - "Circassia in the Nineteenth Century: The Futile Fight for Freedom,", 1986 (Box-folder 145: 11)
    - Grant proposal to the Institute of Turkish Studies for a journal on the Caucasus, 1986 March 7 (Box-folder 145: 12)
    - "Marx on Russians and Muslims,", 1987 (Box-folder 145: 13)
    - "Proposal for a Conference on the Caucasus," submitted to the Kennan Institute, 1988 (Box-folder 145: 14)
    - Book review of Tamara Dragadze's Rural Families in Soviet Georgia, 1988 (Box-folder 145: 15)
    - "Circassian Resistance to Russia,", 1989-1991 (Box-folder 145: 16)
    - "The Last Empire,", 1990 (Box-folder 145: 17)
    - "The North Caucasus: Russia's Long Struggle to Subdue the Circassians,", 1990 August (Box-folder 145: 18)
    - "Notes on a Meeting with Oleg Rumiantsev at the National Endowment for Democracy,", 1990 August 10 (Box-folder 145: 19)
    - "The Demography of the Caucasus According to 1989 Soviet Census Data,", 1991 (Box-folder 145: 20)
    - "Ethnic Dynamics and Dilemmas of the Russian Republic,", 1991 (Box-folder 145: 21)
    - "The Transcaucasus in Transition,", 1991 (Box-folder 145: 22)
    - "Conversation with Galina Starovoitova, Advisor on Interethnic Affairs to the President of the Russian Republic, Boris Yeltsin, at the National Endowment for Democracy,", 1991 October (Box-folder 145: 23)
    - "United States Interests in the Caucasus,", 1991 November (Box-folder 145: 24)
    - "Turkey and Georgia,", 1991 December 15 (Box-folder 145: 25)
    - "Russia and the Chechens: Background to the Confrontations of 1991-1992,", 1992 June (Box-folder 146: 1)
    - "Mission to Chechnia: Daily Notes,", 1992 September-October (Box-folder 146: 2)
    - "An Informal Assessment of the Abkhaz Problem,", 1992 October (Box-folder 146: 3)
    - "Caucasian Madness,", 1992 November (Box-folder 146: 4)
    - Interview of Paul Henze on the situation in Georgia, 1992 November (Box-folder 146: 5)
    - "International Alert Mission to Georgia: Georgia on the Path to Democracy and the Abkhaz Issue,", 1992 November-December (Box-folder 146: 6)
    - "Federalism, Ethnicity and Regional Power Structure,", 1993 (Box-folder 146: 7)
    - "Federalizm, natsional'nye gruppy i struktura regional'noi vlasti v Rossiiskoi Federatsii,", 1993 (Box-folder 146: 8)
    - "Political, Social and Cultural Renewal among the Chechens: Their Future Relationship to Russia and the Outer World," project proposal, 1993 (Box-folder 146: 9)
    - "Conflict in the Caucasus: Background, Problems and Prospects for Mitigation,", 1993 February-1994 (Box-folder 146: 10)
    - "Islam in the North Caucasus: The Example of Chechnia,", 1993 September (Box-folder 146: 11)
    - "The Demography of the RSFSR,", 1994 (Box-folder 146: 12)
    - "Ethnic Dynamics and Dilemmas of the Russian Republic,", 1994 (Box-folder 146: 13)
      Revision of 1991 article with the same title.
    - Review of Moshe Gammer's Muslim Resistance to the Tsar: Shamil and the Conquest of Chechnia and Dagestan, 1994 June (Box-folder 146: 14)
    - Review of Suzanne Goldenberg's Pride of Small Nations: The Caucasus and Post-Soviet Disorder, 1994 (Box-folder 146: 15)
    - Interview with Paul Henze by ITAR-TASS, 1994 December (Box-folder 146: 16)
    - "Letter from Washington," for publication in Georgia Forward, 1994 December (Box-folder 146: 17)
    - "West's Response to the Chechen Crisis,", 1994 December 29 (Box-folder 146: 18)
    - "Georgia in 1995: Recovery Gaining Momentum," (Box-folder 147: 1)
    - "Islam in the North Caucasus: The Example of Chechnia,", 1995 (Box-folder 147: 2)
      Revision of 1993 article with the same title.
    - Review of Ronald Grigor Suny's Looking Toward Ararat: Armenia in Modern History, 1995 April (Box-folder 147: 3)
    - "The Chechens: Perennial Rebels in the Caucasus,", 1995 May (Box-folder 147: 4)
    - "Visit to Georgia,", 1995 May-June (Box-folder 147: 5)
    - "Ajaria 1995: Peace and Poverty in Paradise,", 1995 June (Box-folder 147: 6)
    - Letter to the editor of The Times (London), 1995 December (Box-folder 147: 7)
    - "Russia and the Caucasus,", 1996 (Box-folder 147: 8)
    - "Turkey and Armenia: Past Problems and Future Prospects,", 1996 (Box-folder 147: 9)
    - "Boundaries and Ethnic Groups in Central Asia and the Caucasus: Cause of Conflict and Change?,", 1996 July (Box-folder 147: 10)
    - "Can Moscow Accept the Independence of Ukraine, Georgia, and Azerbaijan?,", 1996 December (Box-folder 147: 11)
    - "Dagestan in October 1997: Imam Shamil Lives!," (Box-folder 147: 12)
    - "Russia and the Caucasus,", 1996 January 14 (Box-folder 147: 13)
    - "Abkhazia Diary, 1997,", 1997 June (Box-folder 147: 14)
    - "Georgia in 1997: A Brief Politico-Economic Assessment,", 1997 August (Box-folder 147: 15)
    - "Was Georgia Ready for Independence?,", 1998 May (Box-folder 148: 1)
    - "Notes on Talk of Aleksei Mozhin, Executive Director for the Russian Federation, International Monetary Fund, at CSIS,", 1998 December 10 (Box-folder 148: 2)
    - "What Does the World Know of Georgia?,", 1999 June (Box-folder 148: 3)
    - "Political Expediency May Have Far Reaching Consequences,", 1999 August 5 (Box-folder 148: 4)
    - "Regional Dynamics in the South Caucasus,", 2000 (Box-folder 148: 5)
    - "Session with Former Russian Prime Minister Yegor Gaidar, Carnegie Endowment,", 2000 January 20 (Box-folder 148: 6)
    - "Turkey's Caucasian Initiatives,", 2001 (Box-folder 148: 7)
    - "Is Putin Capable of Recognizing Russia's Real Interests in the Caucasus?,", 2002 March (Box-folder 148: 8)
    - "American Interest in the Caucasus,", 2002 December (Box-folder 148: 9)
    - "Georgia--Autumn 2007: Withering Roses," (Box-folder 148: 10)
    - "Interview of Paul Henze by Metin Sönmez on Abkhazia,", 2008 August (Box-folder 148: 11)
  - Writings by others, 1983-1995
    - Akbulatov, A., circa 1992 (Box-folder 149: 1)
    - Akhmadov, Iavus and Dalkhan Khozhaev, circa 1992 (Box-folder 149: 2)
    - Avtorkhanov, Abdurakhman, 1994 (Box-folder 149: 3)
    - Colarusso, John, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 149: 4)
    - Fuller, Graham, 1990 (Box-folder 149: 5)
    - Gammer, Moshe, 1990s (Box-folder 149: 6)
    - Goltz, Thomas, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 149: 7)
    - Henze, Mary, 1983 (Box-folder 149: 8)
    - Japaridze, Tedo, 1992 (Box-folder 149: 9)
    - Khasbulatov, Ruslan, undated (Box-folder 149: 10)
    - Kundukh, Aytek, 1987 (Box-folder 149: 11)
    - Muzaev, Timur, 1992 (Box-folder 149: 12)
    - Shevardnadze, Eduard, 1992, 1995 (Box-folder 149: 13)
      Includes order to create a research center on Euro-Asian trade.
    - Tishkov, Valerii, 1990 (Box-folder 149: 14)
    - Vasil'eva, Ol'ga, 1996 (Box-folder 149: 15)
  - Conference files, 1988-2003
    Includes correspondence, programs, notes, papers, reports.
    - "The Russian Advance Toward the Muslim World and the Barrier of the North Caucasus," Society for Central Asian Studies, London, England, 1988 June 16-17 (Box-folder 150: 1)
    - Conference on Soviet Georgia, Kennan Institute, 1989 December (Box-folder 150: 2)
    - "History and Society in Soviet Caucasia," School of Oriental and African Studies, 1990 July 17-19 (Box-folder 150: 3)
    - Roundtable Discussion on South Caucasus, Foreign Service Institute, Department of State, 1992 March 24 (Box-folder 150: 4)
    - Conference on the Contemporary North Caucasus, School of Oriental and African Studies, 1993 April 22-23 (Box-folder 150: 5)
    - Seminar on the Caucasus, National Foreign Affairs Training Center, Arlington, Virginia, 1994 February 22 (Box-folder 150: 6)
    - "Institutions, Identity, and Ethnic Conflict: International Experience and Its Implications for the Caucasus," University of California, Berkeley, 1997 May 2-3 (Box-folder 150: 7)
    - "Narodno-osvoboditel'naia voina narodov Severnogo Kavkaza pod predvoditel'stvom Shamilia i ee mezhdunarodnoe znachenie," Dagestanskii Nauchnii TSentr, Russian Academy of Sciences, Makhachkala, Dagestan, 1997 September (Box-folder 150: 8)
    - Noe Jordania International Conference on Georgia and the Caucasus, Tbilisi, Georgia, 1998 May 26-29 (Box-folder 150: 9)
    - "Georgia: Gateway to Eurasia," America-Georgia Business Development Council, Washington, D.C., 1998 October 5 (Box-folder 150: 10)
    - "Central Asia and the South Caucasus: Re-Orientations, Internal Transitions and Strategic Dynamics," National Intelligence Council, 2000 April 5-7 (Box-folder 150: 11)
    - Conference on GUUAM Organization for Democracy and Economic Development, Center for Strategic and International Studies, 2001 July (Box-folder 150: 12)
    - "Georgia in 2003 and Beyond," sponsored by the American-Georgian Business Council, 2003 April (Box-folder 150: 13)
  - Travel files, 1991-1998
    - Georgia and Turkey, 1991 September-October (Box-folder 151: 1-2)
    - Georgia, 1995 May-June (Box-folder 151: 3-5)
    - Georgia, 1997 May-June (Box-folder 151: 6-9)
    - Azerbaijan and Georgia, 1997 October-November (Box-folder 151: 7-8)
    - Georgia, 1998 May-June (Box-folder 151: 9-10)
  - Research materials, 1856-2009
    - General, 1860-2009
      - Clippings, 1991-2009 (Box-folder 152: 1-9)
      - Collected articles, 1985-2008, undated (Box-folder 152: 10-15)
      - Encyclopedia of Caucasian Ethnic Groups, A-I, 1990s (Box-folder 152: 16)
      - Encyclopedia of Caucasian Ethnic Groups, K-O, 1990s (Box-folder 153: 1)
      - Encyclopedia of Caucasian Ethnic Groups, R-Z, 1990s (Box-folder 153: 2)
      - Etnicheskii sostav naseleniia Severnogo Kavkaza, photocopy, 1974 (Box-folder 153: 3)
      - Sbornik svedenii o kavkazskikh gortsakh, photocopy, 1860 (Box-folder 153: 4)
      - Zakon i obychai na Kavkaz, photocopy, 1890 (Box-folder 153: 5-6)
    - Abkhazia, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 153: 7-11)
    - Abkhazia, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 154: 1-4)
    - Agriculture, 1973 (Box-folder 154: 5)
    - Armenia, 1980-2001 (Box-folder 154: 6-13)
    - Armenian Secret Army for the Liberation of Armenia (ASALA), 1986, 1994 (Box-folder 154: 14)
      See also: Box 49, Folders 14-16.
    - Azerbaijan, 1979-2001 (Box-folder 155: 1-6)
    - Black Sea, 1996 (Box-folder 155: 7)
    - Caspian Sea, 1998 (Box-folder 155: 8)
    - Chechnia, 1964-2005
      - Clippings, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 155: 9-16)
      - Clippings, 1995-2004 (Box-folder 156: 1-8)
      - Collected articles, 1964-1977 (Box-folder 156: 9)
      - Collected articles, 1992-2005 (Box-folder 157: 1-6)
      - Constitution, 1992 (Box-folder 156: 7)
      - Ministerstvo Inostrannykh Del (Ministry of Foreign Affairs) documents, 1992 (Box-folder 157: 8)
        Includes "Bol'shevistskii genotsid chechenskogo naroda" and "Informatsiia o natsional'nom voprose v rasstanovke kadrov v checheno-ingushetii."
      - Photographs, 1992 (Box-folder 147: 9)
        Includes notes by Henze and depicts Dudaev's national guard, the Presidential Palace, and an Easter service in Grozny.
    - Circassia, 1859-2007 (Box-folder 157: 10-11)
      Includes photocopy of Die Bereisung Circassiens by F.A. Kolenati, 1859.
    - Dagestan, 1988-1995, undated (Box-folder 158: 1-3)
    - Georgia, 1992-2009
      - Clippings, 1992-2009 (Box-folder 158: 4-13)
      - Collected articles, 1980-1998 (Box-folder 158: 14-19)
      - Collected articles, 1999-2009 (Box-folder 159: 1-11)
    - Islam, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 159: 12-13)
    - Lezgins, 1997 (Box-folder 159: 14)
    - Linguistics, 1989-1998 (Box-folder 159: 15)
    - Mansur, Sheikh, 1964 (Box-folder 160: 1)
    - Maps, 1990s (Box-folder 160: 2-3)
    - Media, 1998 (Box-folder 160: 4)
    - Shamil, Imam, 1856, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 160: 5-6)
    - Sufism, 1975, 1999 (Box-folder 160: 7-9)
  - Printed matter, 1980-2006
    - AIS News Watch (Armenian Information Service), 1994 (Box-folder 160: 10)
    - Bulletin de l'OAC (Observatoire de l'Asie centrale et du Caucase), 1996-1997 (Box-folder 160: 11)
    - Contemporary Caucasus Newsletter, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 160: 12)
    - The Georgian Chronicle, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 160: 13-14)
    - The Georgian Chronicle, 1995 (Box-folder 161: 1)
    - Georgian Times, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 161: 2-3)
    - Golos Chechenskoi Respubliki, 1992 (Box-folder 161: 4)
    - Ichkeriia, 1997 (Box-folder 161: 5)
    - Impul's, 1992 (Box-folder 161: 6)
    - Informatika, ekonomika, zhizn', 1992 (Box-folder 161: 7)
    - Jamestown Foundation Reports, 2006 (Box-folder 161: 8)
    - Kennan Institute papers, 1980 (Box-folder 161: 9-10)
    - Moskovskie novosti, 1992 (Box-folder 161: 11)
    - Nezavisimaia gazeta, 1992 (Box-folder 161: 12)
    - Respublika (Groznyi), 1992 (Box-folder 161: 13)
    - Severnyi Kavkaz, 1992 (Box-folder 161: 14)
    - Vechernyi Tbilisi, 1991 (Box-folder 161: 15)
  - International Alert missions file, 1991-1992
    - Chechnia mission, 1992
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 162: 1)
      - Notes (Box-folder 162: 2)
      - Reports (Box-folder 162: 3)
    - Georgia mission, 1991-1992
      - Correspondence, 1992 (Box-folder 162: 1)
      - Government documents (Abkhazia), 1992 (Box-folder 162: 5)
      - Government documents (Georgia), 1991 (Box-folder 162: 6)
      - Photograph of Henze and 2 unidentified men, 1992 (Box-folder 162: 7)
      - Reports, 1992 (Box-folder 162: 8)
      - Research materials, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 162: 9-10)
- Central Asia File, 1948-2000 (Box 163-170)
  Contains correspondence, speeches and writings, conference files, reports, proceedings, travel files, clippings, printed matter, and photographs.
  Arranged by physical form, then alphabetically and thereunder chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1972-1995
    - Unidentified, 1989 (Box-folder 163: 1)
    - Routine alphabetical, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 163: 2-3)
    - Fishman, Joshua, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 163: 4)
    - Kasenov, Oumirserik Tulesovich, 1994 (Box-folder 163: 5)
    - Rahul, Ram, 1995 (Box-folder 163: 6)
    - Ruble, Blair, 1989 (Box-folder 163: 7)
  - Speeches and writings, 1948-1999
    - "Soviet Central Asia,", 1948 May 22 (Box-folder 163: 8)
    - "The Economic Development of Soviet Central Asia to the Eve of World War II: An Examination of Soviet Methods as Applied to a Semi-Colonial Area,", 1950 (Box-folder 163: 9)
    - "Politics and Alphabets in Inner Asia,", 1956 January (Box-folder 163: 10)
    - "İç Asya'da Siyaset ve Yazı,", 1956 (Box-folder 163: 11)
    - "Alphabet Changes in Soviet Central Asia and Communist China,", 1957 (Box-folder 163: 12)
    - "Central Asia in the 1980s: Strategic Dynamics in the Decade Ahead,", 1984 (Box-folder 163: 13)
      Written with Alexandre Bennigsen, Marie Broxup and S. Enders Wimbush.
    - "The Central Asian Muslims and Their Brethren Abroad: Marxist Solidarity or Muslim Brotherhood?,", 1985 (Box-folder 163: 14)
    - "Crossroads of High Asia: A Review Article,", 1986 (Box-folder 163: 15)
    - "The Great Game in Kashgaria: British and Russian Missions to Yakub Beg,", 1988 (Box-folder 163: 16)
      Includes Turkish translation, "Kâsgarî'daki Büyük Oyun Yakup Beg Nezdindeki İngiliz ve Rus Temsilcileri."
    - "Independent Kashgaria: Illusion or Practical Possibility?,", 1988 March (Box-folder 163: 17)
    - "From Moscow to Peking in the Era of Glasnost and Perestroika: Impressions and Conversations,", 1988 December (Box-folder 163: 18)
    - "Impressions and Conversations in Uzbekistan and Kazakhstan, September 1988,", 1990 May (Box-folder 163: 19)
    - "Turkestan Rising,", 1992 (Box-folder 164: 1)
    - "Whither Turkestan?,", 1992 (Box-folder 164: 2)
    - "The Changing Dynamics of Central Asia,", 1996 June (Box-folder 164: 3)
    - "Xinjiang and Ex-Soviet Central Asia: Impressions of Chinese Turkestan,", 1996 June (Box-folder 164: 4)
    - "If China Fragments, What Will Be the Consequences?,", 1996 July (Box-folder 164: 5)
    - Book review of Hafeez Malik's Central Asia: Its Strategic Importance and Future Prospects, 1997 (Box-folder 164: 6)
    - "A Continent Transformed: Prospects for Conflict and Change in Eurasia," with S. Enders Wimbush, 1997 February 21 (Box-folder 164: 7)
    - "Uzbekistan Viewed from Ferghana: Situation Normal and Getting Better,", 1998 (Box-folder 164: 8)
    - "U.S. Policy Priorities in Central Asia: Views from the East and South: Report of an Atlantic Council Delegation Visit to China, the Kyrgyz Republic, Tajikistan, Uzbekistan, Pakistan and India,", 1998 June-July (Box-folder 164: 9)
    - "Russia and China: Managing Regional Relations in the Face of Ethnic Aspirations,", 1999 (Box-folder 164: 10)
  - Writings by others, 1990-2000
    - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 164: 11)
    - Engin, Muhabay, undated (Box-folder 164: 12)
    - Fuller, Graham, 1990 (Box-folder 164: 13)
    - Garnett, Sherman, 1997 (Box-folder 164: 14)
    - Gladney, Dru, 1991 (Box-folder 164: 15)
    - Menon, Rajan, 1997 (Box-folder 164: 16)
    - Starr, S. Frederick, 2000 (Box-folder 164: 17)
  - Conference files, 1978-2000
    Includes correspondence, proceedings, papers, and reports.
    - "Soviet Central Asia: Trends and Changes," International Communications Agency, Washington, D.C., 1978 October 31 (Box-folder 165: 1)